Michael Du

Web-Developer

Phone: 415-694-8141 | MDu123@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/michaeldu1 | github.com/supermikol | supermikol.com

Summary

I am a self-motivated developer who appreciates problem-solving at the core of issues. My goal is to work with an open-minded team who place immense value in integrity, mutual support, and open communication.

Skills

- Software: Ruby/Rails, Sinatra, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, PostgresSQL, Python, Git, and Heroku
- Independently Studying: C/Python
- Language: Fluent in verbal/written Mandarin & Cantonese (4+ years residence in China)

Education

Coursera April-July 2016

- Data Structures(Python-based), Verified Certificate: 5JXE3VFXQ5HZ, May 2016
- Algorithm Toolbox(Python-based), Verified Certificate: 3TDD43U3FCZX, May 2016
- Machine Learning (Octave/Linear Algebra), In Progress

Dev Bootcamp - Software Engineer Intensive

October 2015 - February 2016

 Over 19 weeks, accumulated 1000+ hours of programming through building applications using MVC architecture, RESTful routing patterns, and object-oriented design patterns

UCLA - B.A. Degree in Business Economics with Accounting minor

June 2009

• Coursework in econometrics, multivariable calculus, real estate finance, corporate tax

Projects

Kanluqu

In-Progress (Started May 2016)

A fully-functional (but still in-progress) full-stack Rails web app for students to share and view college applications. Incorporates HPE Haven On Demand API to score sentiment for submitted essays.

Github: https://github.com/supermikol/kanlugu

Deployment: kanlugu.herokuapp.com (Please contact me for test login credentials!)

Schema: https://github.com/supermikol/kanluqu/blob/master/schema.png

Thermo-Aggregation Project

February 2016

Utilized infrared thermometer built onto Arduino boards to detect and gather human temperature data that is then sent to and stored in a Rails-API

Contribution: Building Rails-API, configuring Arduino in C, and parsing data between device/API/web-application

Github: https://github.com/WALTERKERR/TAP | **Deployment:** http://thermo-aggregation-project.herokuapp.com | **Presentation:** https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ObS8VA4nx8k (39:20 mark)

Mortar-Analytics March 2016

An experimental business analytics/financial management platform built using Rails and JavaScript **Contribution**: Customizing layout, building Rails-API, creating form for new entries, and building table **Github**: https://github.com/supermikol/mortar-analytics

Experience

Transcend Education (www.cunshande.com) Co-Founder

June 2011 – December 2015

- Founded business in Shenzhen, China from concept to reaching ~\$1 million in annual revenue
- Developed 6-month long program for students to provide character assessment, college counseling, writing workshops, and interview coaching
- Led operations, including recruitment of consultants and board members from the most competitive universities, and providing comprehensive training

Basfood Services Inc. Franchise Operations Manager

June 2009 – December 2010

- Managed and train team of 100+ employees across 4 El Pollo Loco franchises to effectively lower labor and food cost through devising and implementing more stringent practices and procedures
- Prepared financial statements, and reconciled cash flow statements between bank, office, and stores